Hail, oh Fatherland! A thousand times!
Oh Fatherland, Glory be to you! Glory be to you!
Now your breast, your breast, overflows,
Your breast overflows with joy and peace;
And your forehead, your radiant forehead
we contemplate shining more than the Sun,
we contemplate shining more than the Sun.
The firsts, the sons of this soil,
Which proud the Pichincha adorns,
They declared you as their sovereign lady forever
And shed their blood for you.
God observed and accepted the holocaust,
And that blood was the fertile germ
Of other heroes whom the world in astonishment
Saw rise up around you by the thousands.
Rise up by the thousands.
Rise up by the thousands!
Hail, oh Fatherland, a thousand times!
Oh Fatherland, Glory be to you! Glory be to you!
Now your breast, your breast, overflows,
Now your breast overflows with joy and peace;
And your forehead, your radiant forehead
we contemplate shining more than the Sun,
we contemplate shining more than the Sun.